Thelma Finlayson fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Thelma Finlayson fonds
1950 - 1999
F-37
Q99983347
58.5 cm of textual records 258 drawings
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Finlayson, Thelma
Thelma Finlayson is a distinguished entomologist who served as a professor in the Department of Biological Sciences at Simon Fraser University from 1967 until her retirement in 1979. Her research interests have centered on the classification of immature stages of insect parasites of forest and agricultural pests. Since 1979 she has been Professor Emerita and continues to be actively involved with the university, contributing time, counsel and private funds. The university established the Thelma Finlayson Society in 1989 in honour of her many contributions to SFU.
published
Full
Revised
The title is based on the name of the records creator.
Fonds consists of records made or received by Thelma Finlayson. Records reflect Professor Finlayson's research interests, teaching activities, administrative service to SFU, and participation in scholarly organizations. Includes correspondence, referee reports, lecture schedules, midterm exams, final exams, marking schemes, laboratory lessons, newsletters, agendas, publications, press releases, newspaper clippings, drawings and graphs.
Fonds is arranged into 5 series:
1. Correspondence
2. SFU subject files
3. Publications
4. Course files
5. Drawings
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Department of Biological Sciences; Graphic materials; Textual records; Science and technology; Education
All accessions have been processed as of December 2015. No further accruals are expected.
The records were donated to the Simon Fraser University Archives by Dr. Thelma Finlayson in two accessions. The first accession was received in 1992 and the second was received in 2010.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available. Additional biographical material selected by Thelma Finlayson is available in the hard copy version of the finding aid maintained in the Archives Reading Room.
- Correspondence, 1957 - 1999; F-37-1; 28.5 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of correspondence made or received by Thelma Finlayson. Activities and topics documented include entomological research, the publication of Professor Finalyson's scholarly papers, adjudicating other scholars' research, providing recommendations for academic positions, and service in professional organizations.
  One file contains correspondence regarding the publication of a two-volume work on the immature stages of insects. This work represented the first new information on this subject in over 100 years.
  Textual records
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. File numbers F-37-1-0-0-26 and F-37-1-0-0-27 are Restricted in Whole. However, the remaining files in this series are open. Please see the file list for this series and consult the archivist for more details.
  - Correspondence - Belleville, 1957 - 1966; F-37-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
    Open
  - Correspondence - general, 1967; F-37-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1968; F-37-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1969; F-37-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1970; F-37-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1971; F-37-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1972; F-37-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1973; F-37-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1974; F-37-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1975; F-37-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1976; F-37-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1977; F-37-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1978; F-37-1-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1979; F-37-1-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1980; F-37-1-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1981; F-37-1-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1982; F-37-1-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1983; F-37-1-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1984; F-37-1-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1985; F-37-1-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1986; F-37-1-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - general, 1987; F-37-1-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 37-1)
  - Correspondence - Campopleginae Monograph, 1964 - 1973; F-37-1-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 37-2)
  - Correspondence - publications, 1968 - 1990; F-37-1-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 37-2)
  - Correspondence - publication on immature insects, 1969 - 1988; F-37-1-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 37-2)
  - Correspondence - recommendations, 1968 - 1973; F-37-1-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 37-2)
    Restricted in whole
  - Correspondence - recommendations, 1978 - 1991; F-37-1-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 37-2)
  - Correspondence - Entomological Society of America, 1971 - 1975; F-37-1-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 37-2)
  - Correspondence - referee reports, 1972 - 1989; F-37-1-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 37-2)
  - Correspondence - Gypsy Moth committee, 1978 - 1979; F-37-1-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 37-2)
  - Correspondence - Robert Carlson, 1973; F-37-1-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 37-2)
  - Correspondence - Spruce worm spraying, 1977; F-37-1-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 37-2)
  - Correspondence - David Wahl, 1983 - 1994; F-37-1-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 37-2)
  - Correspondence - general, 1988 - 1999; F-37-1-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 37-3)
  - Correspondence - Aphidiidae - "The Systematics and Taxonomy of Final-Instar Larvae of the Family Aphidiidae (Hymenoptra)", 1969 - 1987; F-37-1-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Correspondence - Insect Identification, 1969 - 1982; F-37-1-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Correspondence - "The Cephalic Structures and Spiracles of Final - Instar Larvae of the Family Aphidiidae (Hymenoptera)" publication, 1989 -1993; F-37-1-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
- SFU subject files, 1973 - 1991; F-37-2; 8 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to Professor Finlayson's administrative service and membership in Academic Women. Includes correspondence and newsletters.
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. File numbers F-37-2-0-0-1 and F-37-2-0-0-6 are Restricted in Whole. However, the remaining files in this series are open. Please see the file list for this series and consult the archivist for more details.
  - SFU University Appointments Committee, 1973; F-37-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 37-3)
  - SFU Women's Committee, 1976 - 1977; F-37-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 37-3)
  - SFU Academic Women, 1988 - 1991; F-37-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 37-3)
  - SFU T. Finlayson appointment to full professor, 1975 - 1976; F-37-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 37-3)
  - SFU T. Finlayson report on Sabbatical Leave, 1978; F-37-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 37-3)
  - SFU - Academic Advice Centre Acting Director's report, 1979; F-37-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 37-3)
- Publications, 1957 - 1978; F-37-3; 1 cm of textual records
  - Winter Moth news clippings, 1977 - 1978; F-37-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 37-3)
- Course files, 1969 - 1979; F-37-4; 16 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to classes that Professor Finlayson taught at Simon Fraser University including Biological Sciences 102 and Biological Sciences 317 (Entomology). Includes lecture schedules, midterm exams, final exams, marking schemes, and laboratory lessons.
  - Biological Sciences 102, 1971; F-37-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 37-3)
  - Biological Sciences 102, 1976 - 1979; F-37-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 37-3)
  - Biological Sciences 317, 1969; F-37-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317, 1970; F-37-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317, 1971; F-37-4-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317, 1972; F-37-4-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317, 1972; F-37-4-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317, 1973; F-37-4-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317, 1973; F-37-4-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317, 1974; F-37-4-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317, 1975; F-37-4-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317, 1976; F-37-4-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317, 1978; F-37-4-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317 - Lab 1-12, [ca 1975]; F-37-4-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
  - Biological Sciences 317 - Lab 1-7, 1972 - 1978; F-37-4-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 37-4)
- Drawings, 1950 - 1990; F-37-5; 5 cm of textual records 258 drawings
  Series consists of illustrations and graphs by Thelma Finlayson and copies of publications written or co-authored by her. Drawings depict structure and detail of larvae, cocoons, puparia, spiracles, and other insect anatomy. File F-37-5-0-0-10 and files numbered from F-37-5-0-0-12 through to F-37-5-0-0-35 are drawings associated with "The Systematics and Taxonomy of final-instar larvae of the family Aphidiidae (Hymenoptera)" publication, which is protected by copyright, and the copyright for these drawings subsits with the Entomological Society of Canada.
  Graphic materials; Textual records
  - Drawings (22) for paper by T. Finlayson - The Cephalic Structures and Spiracles of Final-Instar Larvae of the Subfamil Campopleginae, Tribe Campoplegini (Hymenoptera: Ichneumonidae) 1/2, 1975; F-37-5-0-0-1 (Cabinet MC 39-14)
    Textual records; Graphic materials
  - Drawings (28) for paper by T. Finlayson - The Cephalic Structures and Spiracles of Final-Instar Larvae of the Subfamil Campopleginae, Tribe Campoplegini (Hymenoptera: Ichneumonidae) 2/2, 1975; F-37-5-0-0-2 (Shelf Map cabinet)
    Graphic materials
  - Drawings (2) for paper by T. Finlayson - Final-Instar Larvae of a Wood-Boring Beetle, Tetropium Velutinum Le Conte (Coleoptera: Cerambycidae), 1969; F-37-5-0-0-3 (Cabinet MC 39-14)
  - Drawings (1) for paper by T. Finlayson - Final-Instar Larvae of Coleocentrus Rufus (Hymenoptera: Ichneumonidae), 1970; F-37-5-0-0-4 (Cabinet MC 39-14)
  - Drawings (5) for paper by T. Finlayson - The Hymenopterous Parasites (Hymenoptera: Aphidiidae et Aphelinidae) of the Pea Aphid in Eastern North America, 1967; F-37-5-0-0-5 (Cabinet MC 39-14)
  - Drawings (13) for paper by R.W. Smith and T. Finlayson - Larvae of Dipterous Parasites of Nymphal and Adult Grasshoppers, 1950; F-37-5-0-0-6 (Cabinet MC 39-15)
  - Drawings (10) for paper by T. Finlayson - Taxonomy of Cocoons and Puparia, and their Contents, of Canadian Parasites of Neodiprion sertifer (Geoff.) (Hyamenoptera: Diprionidae), 1960; F-37-5-0-0-7 (Cabinet MC 39-15)
  - Drawings (13) for paper by T. Finlayson - Taxonomy of Final-Instar Larvae of the Hymenopterous and Dipterous Parasites of Acrobasis Spp. (Lepidoptera: Phycitidae) in the Ottawa Region, 1967; F-37-5-0-0-8 (Cabinet MC 39-15)
  - Drawings (19) for paper by T. Finlayson - Taxonomy of Cocoons and Puparia, and their Contents, of Canadian Parasites of Diprion hercyniae (Htg.) (Hyamenoptera: Diprionidae), 1960; F-37-5-0-0-9 (Cabinet MC 39-15)
  - Drawings (9) from "The Systematics and Taxonomy of Final-Instar Larvae of the Family Aphidiidae (Hymenoptra)", [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Graphs - "The Systematics and Taxonomy of Final-Instar Larvae of the Family Aphidiidae (Hymenoptra)", [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Aphidius Gifuensis, Aphidius Hortensis, Aphidius Longipetiolus ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (1) - Aphidius Lupini from "The Systematics and Taxonomy of Final-Instar Larvae of the Family Aphidiidae (Hymenoptra)" - Thelma Finlayson Biology, [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-13 (Cabinet MC 39-15)
  - Drawings (3) - Aphidius Matricariae, Aphidius Nigripes, Aphidius Obscuripes ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Aphidius Ribis, Aphidius Rosae, Aphidius Salicis ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (4) - Aphidius Sicarius, Lysaphidus Arvensis, Lysaphidus Pleotrichophoric, Diaerettiella Rapae ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (7) - Monoctonus (Faliconus) sp, Monoctonus (Monoctouus) Cerasi, Monoctonus (Monoctouus) Crepedis ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Lipolexis Scutellaris, Trioxys (Betuloxys) Compressicoruis, Trioxys (Trioxys) nr Cirsii ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) -Trioxys (Trioxys) Complantus, Trioxys (Trioxys) Pallidus, Binodoxys (Binodoxys) sp ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (2) -Binodoxys (Fissicaudus) Confucius Acanthocaudus Schlingeri ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) -Lysiphlebus (Adialytus) Salicaphis, Lysiphlebus (Phlebus) Fabarum, Lysiphlebus Testaceipes ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Lysiphlebia Japonica, Calaphidius Watanabei, Pauesia Abietis ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Pauesia Infulata, Pauesia Inouyei, Pauesia Japonica ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Pauesia Pini, Pauesia Ponderosae, Pauesia Procephali ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Pauesia Takomaeusis, Pauesia Unilachis, Xenostigmus Bifasciatus ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Diaeretus Leucopterus, Euaphidius Areolatus, Euaphidius Cingulatus ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Euaphidius Setiger, Aphidius Alius, Aphidius Aquilis ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Aphidius Avenaphis, Aphidius Confusus, Aphidiius Floridaensis ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Ephedrus incompletus, Ephedrus Lacertosus, Ephedrus Niger ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Ephedrus Persicae, Ephedrus Plagiator, Ephedrus Robustus ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (9) - Toxares Deltiger & Spirecles from "The Systematics and Taxonomy of Final-Instar Larvae of the Family Aphidiidae (Hymenoptra)" - Thelma Finlayson Biology, [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Praon Exsoletum Palitaus, Praon Myzophagum, Praon Orientale ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (9) - Praon Simulaus, Praon Union, Praon Dorsale, Praon Exsoletum Exsoletum, Praon Exsoletum Palitaus ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawings (3) - Praon Aguti, Praon Dorsale, Praon Exsoletum Exsoletum ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 37-5)
  - Drawing (1) - Pauesia Konoi from "The Systematics and Taxonomy of Final-Instar Larvae of the Family Aphidiidae (Hymenoptra)", [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-35 (Cabinet MC 39-15)
  - Drawings (52) - Figures 78-92, Figures 93-116, Figures 128-138 ..., [1970?] - 1990; F-37-5-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 37-5)